Mekayla Trujillo

Phone: (432) 853-4199 | Email: mickeytrj@gmail.com | Odessa, TX 79763

LinkedIn: Mekayla Trujillo | GitHub: Mekayla Trujillo | Portfolio Link

Professional Statement

Front-end web developer currently enrolled in the Coding Boot Camp at the University of Texas at Austin with a high interest in developing intuitive user experiences on mobile and web applications. Strengths in creativity, understanding new concepts, approaching and solving coding concepts and issues, offers strong collaboration and assistance when working with others.

Technical Skills and Career Qualifications

Coding Languages: Javascript, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Responsive Web Design, Web APIs

Applications: Git, GitHub

Coding Tools: Bootstrap, jQuery

Programs: Microsoft Office 365 Programs, iOS-based iWork Productivity programs, Google Doc

Editors, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, iMovie, Procreate

Career Skills: Writing, editing, organization, interpersonal skills, clerical skills, communication, strong computing skills, and knowledge of the Windows (Microsoft) and iOS (Macintosh) operating systems

Coding Projects

Top 3 - Taco Shops | GitHub Repository Link | Deployed Website

- Summary: A taco shop website highlighting the top three taco shops in Austin, TX.
- Role: Front-End Developer, GitHub repository manager, assisted with fellow group members on design and API implementation
- **Tools:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Materialize, Mapbox GL JS, OpenWeather OneCall API, iQuery

Web API Coding Quiz | GitHub Repository Link | Deployed Website

- **Summary:** A timed coding quiz that allows users to understand their knowledge of JavaScript.
- Role: Sole Front-End DeveloperTools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Vacation! A Weather Dashboard | GitHub Repository Link | Deployed Website

- **Summary:** A weather dashboard that shows the current day forecast and five-day forecasts for your future travel destination.
- Role: Sole Front-End Developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Moment.js, OpenWeather OneCall API

Experience

Substitute Teacher Ector County Independent School District

2019 - present Odessa, TX

Served as a substitute teacher for various schools for the Ector County Independent School District.

Key Accomplishments:

- Taught through the use of educational instruction and alternative work provided by the teacher in their absence. Facilitated students for additional assignments performed various monitor duties and provided strong classroom organization skills if required.
- For the district in the 2020-2021 school year, was assigned as a **Permanent Substitute Teacher** at Murry Fly Elementary School, a campus that is part of the school district.

Permanent Substitute Teacher Murry Fly Elementary School

2020-2021 Odessa. TX

For the 2020-2021 school year, served as the day-to-day permanent substitute teacher for the Murry Fly Elementary School campus only.

Key Accomplishments:

- Taught and mentored elementary students through alternative educational instruction.
- Facilitated students for additional assignments and events when required. Performed various monitoring duties on the campus, classroom organization skills, and strong interpersonal skills when teaching and helping students on campus alongside communicating effectively with other educators and staff members on campus.
- Aside from subbing, also served as a teachers' aide to select classrooms on days when no substitute teacher was required on campus.
- At times when not required in a classroom or as an aide, served as an alternative secretary
 and office assistance for the front office. Demonstrated clerical skills, including answering
 phone calls, the organization, and confidential handling of records and paperwork. Assisted
 teachers, parents, students, and other employees of ECISD when necessary.

Education

The University of Texas of Austin – Coding Bootcamp Accomplishing feat of Full Stack Web Development Certificate

2021 - present Austin, TX

Currently enrolled in an online part-time Coding Bootcamp through the University of Texas at Austin to obtain a certificate in Full Stack Web Development.

- Currently practicing and acquiring web development and technical skills.
 - Demonstrates strong knowledge of web programming languages and technical skills in HTML, CSS, Responsive Design for Websites and Mobile, Javascript, AJAX, Web APIs, ¡Query, Bootstrap, and Git/GitHub deployment.

The University of Texas of the Permian Basin Bachelors of Arts in Psychology and English

2015 - 2019 Odessa, TX

Public accredited university in Odessa, Texas. Further developed career-related and personal skills from attendance and academic accomplishments.

- Developed and assisted on student projects such as a student-run novel.
- Senior Honors Thesis for Psychology major covered the projection of one's satisfaction with the performance of their favorite hobby.
- 4.000 GPA from enrollment, 3.420 cumulative total.

Academic Honors and Projects Honors

The University of Texas of the Permian Basin

- Dean's Honor Roll List. Fall 2017 & Fall 2018.
 - Prestigious President's List. Spring 2019.

Projects

<u>Great Explications – Some Related to Art, Some Related to Culture, and Some out of Left Field</u>

Compiled work of articles relating to modern pop culture and entertainment. Composed in the Advanced Composition course of Dr. Babcock in the Fall 2017 semester.

<u>Senior Honor Thesis – Pursuing Activities in a Positive Manner</u>

A Psychology thesis completed in the Spring 2019 semester with the assistance of Mrs. Fife. Investigated the project of one's satisfaction rate with the performance of their favorite hobby.